The RNN component of
图像说明网络的 RNN 组件
the captioning network is trained on the captions in the COCO dataset.
是用 COCO 数据集中的图像说明训练的
We're aiming to train the RNN to predict
我们的目标是训练 RNN 根据之前的单词
the next word of a sentence based on previous words.
预测句子的下个单词
But, how exactly can it train on string data?
但是如何用字符串数据训练它呢？
Neural networks do not do well with strings.
神经网络在字符串上的训练效果不好
They need a well-defined numerical alpha to effectively
它们需要明确定义的数值输出
perform back propagation and learn to produce similar output.
来有效地执行反向传播并学习生成相似的输出
So, we have to transform the captioned associated
因此 我们需要将与图像关联的说明
with the image into a list of tokenize words.
转换为标记化的单词列表
This tokenization turns any strings into a list of integers.
这种标记化操作会将任何字符串转换为整数列表
So how does this tokenization work?
标记化的原理是什么？
First, we iterate through all of the training captions and create
首先 我们遍历所有训练说明
a dictionary that maps all unique words to a numerical index.
并创建一个字典 将所有唯一单词映射到数值索引
So, every word we come across,
因此 对于我们遇到的每个单词
will have a corresponding integer value that we can find in this dictionary.
都可以在这个字典中找到相应的整数值
The words in this dictionaries are referred to as our vocabulary.
这个字典中的单词称为词汇表
The vocabulary typically also includes a few special tokens.
词汇表通常还包含几个特殊标记
In this example, we'll add two special tokens to our dictionary,
在此示例中 我们将向字典中添加两个特殊标记
a start and end token that indicates the start and the end of a sentence.
&lt;start&gt; 和 &lt;end&gt; 标记 表示句子的起始和结束位置
Now, the entire vocabulary is the length of the number of unique words
整个词汇表的长度是训练数据集中的唯一单词数量加上 2
in our training dataset plus two for the start and end tokens.
即起始和结束标记
Let's take a look at this sample caption.
我们来看看这个示例说明
A person doing a trick on a rail while riding a skateboard.
“A person doing a trick while riding a skateboard.”
This caption is then converted into a list of tokens with
此说明被转换成标记列表
the special start and end tokens marking the beginning and end of the sentence.
包含特殊的起始和结束标记 表示句子的起始和结尾处
This list of token is then turned into a list of integers which come from
这个标记列表然后被转换成整数列表
our dictionary that maps each distinct word in the vocabulary to an integer value.
这些整数来自将词汇表中的独特单词映射到整数值的字典
This one more step before these words gets sent as
在将这些单词作为输入发送给 RNN 之前
input to an RNN and that's the embedding layer,
还有一步 也就是嵌入层
which transform each word in a caption into a vector of a desired consistent shape.
嵌入层将说明中的每个单词转换为一个向量 这些向量具有预期的一致形状
After this embedding step,
在此嵌入步骤之后
we're finally ready to train an RNN that can
我们最终准备好训练 RNN
predict the most likely next word in a sentence.
它能够预测句子中的下个概率最高的单词